All right, so now we're going to discuss the consolidation Apex.
So, generally, you know, as the run, it runs and it runs and it runs,
after you've had these pauses, after you've had the continuation,
and generally as well, prices extended past some level into a higher time frame feeding fractal.
So let's just say down here, this was a daily pickup, prices run,
there's a core daily base here, is very, very likely.
we're going to get responses out of these daily levels right because they're pulling thick levels of liquidity
okay provided the you know the core base on the cell side here um has some form of unflow liquidity
left at the top the middle or the bottom etc now generally what happens is you know price can
extend extremely inefficiently okay so we want that into the level that already peaks our interest
already and if we can go into a small pause price clusters and then it has a mini release again
okay now it's those last second last releases that we're looking at to get the entry okay
it is required a lot of engagement okay but generally speaking what will be happening here is
price will slow down it would show signs of faltering sometimes around this area
it might feed back in okay into the shell on the way the top of the shelf was picked
it might feed back in picking up whatever liquidity is in the shell and then running and that to us is a
shelf wash extension okay we always want my inefficient extension if price
clusters in towards the level we're not gonna try and catch the high that
doesn't mean we can't catch these retests okay that doesn't mean we can't
cast these retests ultimately we're not gonna try to catch the high if price
drifts into the level we want that inefficient leg we want that release we want
that parabolic phase which we're gonna look at the minute as a constituent
feature of a high that to increase the probabilities but generally what can
happen is price can go into a drift mode like this, okay, especially on the higher time frame
runs. And inside this drift mode, this consolidation, you're going to see individual price
runs. So from the base, it can run, dry out, come pick up liquidity and enter a bit of a, you
know, consolidation which can have all the constituent features of a price run, okay, inside of
that consolidation. It would just be wide arranging. You'd have to
zoom in to see those constituent features but price can pause okay and then you want that
release to look for that unfilled liquidity once we get it bump there's a short there and always
sometimes price won't consolidate okay sometimes price will just go straight to the level and draw
right back down okay how do we differentiate is just as you know you're going to have to make the
decision which type of setup is your favorite okay you engage you engage and you engage
you find the probable, the preferable kind of anatomy into the level.
You might find you can take both, you're confident and taking both the straight release into the unfiled level,
and also they pause and release, also the shelf wash extension.
Where the top was picked, price bleeds into the bottom, and then it extends,
picking up all the inventory of buyers, releasing it, leaving it vulnerable.
They're generally quicker breaking down trades.
Those kind of trades would break down quicker.
But ultimately, what happens here is you're going to have a base, okay?
There's going to be a base, apex base.
That price is staying on top.
And once you put in the high, once price has picked up the liquidity from the level,
once it's coming to that unfiled level, this high needs to help.
Okay, it just needs to help.
Now, what you're on the preferable ones, the preferable highs,
what you see is price comes and you get weaker and weaker.
and weaker rallies until it breaks down.
Okay, and then this break can be quite fast and profound
into someone field level of liquidity below.
Sometimes, if price has some liquidity left over here,
okay, like the top was picked there.
It can come to the bottom and go all the way back higher
to the high for a swing retest.
Okay, and that's the most worrisome because these moves will be quite fast.
That is more likely to happen if two variables are present.
variables are present in price.
There's unfilled liquidity inside the apex and the way price extended into the
unfilled liquidity was quite fast.
Okay, so what generally happened is volatility would increase price would pump
after this consolidation come right back down into the unfilled area and pump right back
up and generally, you know, that can, sorry about that.
So yeah, generally price can shit, shit itself right back down to the infield liquidity
and then shoot right back up, this exposed open.
leg into the core base okay and that will be a fractal apex base retest okay just in the lower time frame
and then you know by this point in looking for breakdowns again this could be the higher time frame
broader apex base which is going to be sitting on a shell um and this here would be the breakout accumulation
which push price back down and very often you know price can come and then depending on what liquidity
is left over here, price can draw back up this extension again, pick up liquidity from the
breakout accumulation, and continue on its merry way. So it doesn't matter what kind of liquidity
is left down in the middle as well. Yes, we're expecting price to ultimately trade through
the mid-price run levels, but who says it can't come to the mid-price run level, respond,
and then continue. Okay? So it's all about the nature of how price extends.
But right now we're focusing on the consolidation apex.
So let's look at an example, right?
There's two different examples here.
So there's one, this is a really, really, really good one.
So these are the ones I like.
Price comes, okay, picks up some side
and clearly what you see is,
comes into liquidity here, absorb inside the hat.
Comes into the next bit of liquidity,
absorb inside the next, the most local inventory.
And then past that point,
there's a breakdown, a shift in the state,
and price goes in the price room, okay,
to some unfilled liquidity.
Now in this case, okay,
this is actually a H4 level.
The top side was picked, it comes to the bottom,
because of the nature of the extension,
it gets past its inventory of the move down,
and it goes in a run,
responding off some residual levels,
but ultimately it goes to the right,
to the unfilled part at the high,
okay, because of the nature of the leftover liquidity here.
Okay, very, very often,
there won't be any liquidity here.
and price will find no problem after it flips beneath a shelf like that
it will find no problem in
you know get an absorb inside here and then continue it down very very often
but in this case it wasn't the case okay there was a very big area of unfil liquidity here
and price goes for a swing re-test at the high how do you differentiate between that
you can track the runs very closely when you look at the fractal nature of price
but you the more you exercise the more you engage okay you
you're gonna find these variations,
gonna be able to spot these variations to a better,
you know, a more proficient degree, okay?
So that's one variation.
Then you have, sometimes, let's look at this one,
and you have something like this,
price comes into a level,
on the way the fuckback came into,
definitely comes into a level,
ah, yeah, they do come into a level.
There's so many levels inside that week is ridiculous,
but it does come into a level,
it draws right back,
back down okay there is a bit of a shelf here okay picks the shelf up and it runs it
out to new highs extending so first of all we're just picking up the inventory of
liquidity picking up running it out and then we had that inefficient extension
into a residual level then this is the inventory see price comes failing to push
failing to push and then you have your shift we know this level is most likely
deltoff because it was run higher was picked up and run higher deltoth washed picked up some
sellers and the nature of how far prices extended from here to here you know it left it quite
wonderful in this case there's probably a pocket rocket here and it pocket rocket there
um so look yeah fuck yeah it's responded there this is your shelf this effectively came
very often what you might see is a deeper pick-up down to here but it doesn't it comes
near enough to a clean breaking point forms a base and then this high is contained inside here
by that point the shift this shifting liquidity has already occurred i.e. put in the high picked
up sellers we shifted the shell we're expecting this to be residual okay also the time of day
can influence what kind of response you're going to get at this level so here this is 7 p.m.
at 5 p.m. Sorry, 6 p.m. And by that point, liquidity is trying out the market.
Okay, we're not expecting to fire price to keep pushing. And it basically perpetuates price
into a bit of a range. And then you open up the next day, some accumulation here.
You have to get out of the way. It's absorbed. Comes picks up the last bit of liquidity.
And then by that point, you know, made this merry way. Again, there's a price pause.
And this whole area really on a broader time frame is a price pause. Okay. Now,
shit now that's just one or two examples of highs let's have a look at gold okay
because these are some pretty good examples all right it's going to daily
week off now we're looking at daily examples there right just to show you how
consistent these apex bases are but as puts in the high comes to the shelf we can't
RICO rallies and then generally can come back up to pick up liquidity okay high this will be
We have a different one, look at the nature of the extension.
It doesn't necessarily cluster this time round,
but it has a base.
You get beneath that base to the shift.
We pick up residual, draw right back up the extension leg,
picking up the apex, and continue.
And of course, when we're taking these retest trades,
we want to clearly identify with shell
and then the accumulation which pushed past the shell
to be able to take that trade and define our risk.
But yeah, so that's just how I like to trade,
take these shell flip apex based retest trades,
especially on the high timeframe.
The same way you're getting this retest at this daily apex, the same thing can happen at this height, the one minute, the one hour, the five minute, etc.
Okay, so apex price comes and picks up this fractal, okay, let's zoom into it, it already picks up this fractal.
Okay, here you go. So this will be a lower time for example. There would be the high price came, picked up the bottom, transfer and liquidity. Now that has an inventory.
This is like the daily shelf really. Price extends.
right into this base, not enough liquidity by that point because we would have had,
we already would have flipped the shelf on H4, the one hour, this already would have been picking
up a higher time frame level, but because the nature of this shelf, there's a big, big amount
of liquidity inside here. As you can see, price has to deal it off for a while, but that's
beside the point. Price extends pixel liquidity. The remaining liquidity here is absorbed
inside this, that accumulation there, which pushed price back.
down or pushed it down.
Okay, the same applies with this is coming into unfilled liquidity.
Okay, very, very precise runs because this level is largely picked up.
You get a response at these levels, but ultimately it goes back to the high and this
would be a swing retest of the apex base, okay?
This is more of a price retest of the apex base.
Okay, this one could consider a swing retest of the apex base.
You know, it could have easily extended it.
back up into there but you see these wicks okay what's happening is price is
breaking down drawing back up the apex and continue okay i'm not going to make this
particular video too long it's gone a five minute because in the next one we got you're going to
cover more deeply the apex base we test okay here you have an apex price pumps
or drops off filling this inefficiency into some fractal level there draws back up to the
accumulation which pushed it back down that's an apex base for you
test okay so sometimes depending on the nature of the inventory here this will
dictate where the price comes back deeper for its top side it will dictate
where the price can easily just move through it or dictate whether I saw to pick
the top comes it grabs the bottom and it runs washing this inventory away that
will further dictate how price moves back down through it okay there's very very
specific features and the more you engage the more you exercise you're gonna
come across these variations and these
different scenarios.
You're going to find niches inside them.
So you can be a master of picking highs,
having a deep connection with all the different variation,
the high probability patterns at the highs,
and being able to trade that, that, the high,
even that, maybe this counterflow.
And you know, this will become your niche effectively.
Forget this one.
You'll also know how far price can extend.
What instance says price is likely to extend,
no, the different different variations.
And that is where the real skill is built.
That is the real, you know,
We will cover these examples time and time again as they come across, okay, in real live
examples or weekly examples when discussing price on a weekly basis.
But the issue is that's my understanding and I can point everything out to you, but you
need to internalize it on your own.
So you have to go through the process of internalizing structured engagement, etc.
Now also I'm going to do is, I'm talking about this conceptually on historical examples.
I have some examples already.
I have quite a few examples already of trade examples and real constituent parts of these price swings explained in real life
in real live examples as price is moving and that offers much more context.
Okay, it actually goes into the minute details of how price is moving and naturally you're going to learn more in the life conditions to get a field for the context and price to get a field for how price moves in a different variant states
that is where the real learning is done, but ideally, you know, you want to be able to spot these price behaviors prior to even looking
to spot them on live that's where you look at historical examples and that's why we're
going over this series okay but yeah we'll cover the apex based retest and
shove top bottom retest maybe as well okay